CHEAM HUEY WEN

+60 12-7040924 • hueywen.cheam@gmail.com • Selangor, Malaysia www.linkedin.com/in/cheam-huey-wen • Portfolio

SUMMARY

Recent graduate with skills in Python, R, Excel, Tableau, and Power Bl. Experienced in analyzing data and creating dashboards to support business decisions. Motivated to apply technical expertise and problem-solving skills to contribute to organizational success.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Account Executive, MJ Life (Malaysia) Sdn. Bhd.

Sep 2022 - Aug 2024

- Developed custom reports and dashboards in Google Sheets to support business decisions.
- Analyzed sales data to improve workflows, boosting productivity and client engagement.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, enhancing project success rates by 10%.

Customer Service Associate, MJ Life (Malaysia) Sdn. Bhd.

Nov 2021 - Sep 2022

- Maintained accurate customer and inventory data for analysis and reporting.
- Monitored inventory levels, analyzed trends, and recommended stock optimizations.
- Prepared reports on customer service trends and feedback using Excel and data visualization tools to guide team strategies.

Information Technology Intern, Seeka Limited

Jul 2021 - Oct 2021

- Coordinated project tasks to ensure compliance with standards and regulations
- Conducted quality checks to verify the accuracy of scraped data and its alignment with project requirements.

EDUCATION

Master of Data Science

Oct 2022 - Mar 2024

University of Malaya

- Relevant coursework in Data Analytics, Data Mining, and Big Data Management.
- CGPA 3.95

Bachelor of Science in Cognitive Science

Oct 2018 - Oct 2021

University Malaysia Sarawak

- Relevant coursework in Artificial Intelligence, Virtual Reality, Cognitive Neuroscience,
 Object-Oriented programming, and Human Factors and Ergonomics.
- CGPA 3.78

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Technical Skills: Python, R, C++, Power BI, Tableau, Machine Learning, Figma, Google Sheets
- Languages: English, Mandarin, Malay
- Certifications: British Airways Data Science Job Simulation (Forage), BCG Data Science Job Simulation (Forage), Data Analysis with Python (freecodecamp), PWC Power BI Job simulation